Everyone gets tired – it's a normal part of human existence.
每个人都会感到疲惫——这是人类生存的正常状态。
It can make us grouchy and grumpy at the end of the day, but a good night's sleep will often leave us feeling well rested.
一天结束时，疲惫会让我们脾气暴躁、心情烦躁，但一夜好眠通常会让我们感觉精力恢复。
However, sometimes we feel more than just general tiredness.
然而，有时我们感受到的不只是普通的疲惫。
We can get overtired and feel a bit run-down which may affect our daily lives – but what can we do about it?
我们会过度劳累、精神萎靡，这可能会影响日常生活——但我们该如何应对呢？
Here are some things that may stop you getting overtired.
以下是一些能帮你避免过度疲惫的方法。
Being very tired frequently could be the result of lifestyle choices: poor diet, lack of exercise, or an inefficient routine.
频繁感到极度疲惫可能是生活方式选择导致的：饮食不佳、缺乏锻炼，或是作息效率低下。
For some people, changes to their habits and routines could help them to beat bouts of extreme tiredness.
对一些人来说，改变习惯和作息有助于摆脱一阵阵的极度疲惫。
First, let's look at physical health.
首先，我们来看看身体健康。
According to the UK National Health Service (NHS) website, eating healthy meals and snacks regularly, around 3-4 times per day, could improve your energy levels.
英国国家医疗服务体系（NHS）官网指出，规律进食健康的正餐和快餐，每天约3至4次，能够提升你的精力水平。
Giving your body the fuel it needs could help you to be more energised, and therefore, less tired.
为身体提供所需的能量能让你更有活力，进而减少疲惫感。
If you're feeling overtired, you might not want to exercise.
如果你感到过度劳累，或许不想运动。
However, regular physical activity may actually mean you are less tired in general.
然而，规律的体育锻炼实际上通常可能会让你不那么疲惫。
Activities like jogging or cycling could also help you get fitter.
慢跑、骑行等运动还能让你更健康。
And being more active could help you to lose weight, which can also aid you in the battle against tiredness.
增加活动量有助于减重，这也能帮你对抗疲惫。
Those extra kilos from being overweight put a strain on your heart, which can lead to you feeling more tired.
超重带来的多余体重会给心脏造成负担，进而让你更易感到疲惫。
Another thing that can leave us feeling weary and drained is stress.
另一个让我们感到疲惫不堪、精力耗尽的因素是压力。
Reducing your stress levels may help you to feel less tired on a regular basis.
降低压力水平有助于你减少日常的疲惫感。
Taking up an activity like yoga or going for a walk could help you to unwind and feel more refreshed.
开始做瑜伽、散步等活动能帮你放松身心、恢复精力。
And you may think if you're feeling tired, that a good cup of coffee will perk you up.
你或许觉得疲惫时喝一大杯咖啡就能提神。
However, the Royal College of Psychiatrists recommends anyone feeling tired to cut down on their caffeine intake, especially after mid-afternoon, to get better sleep at night.
然而，英国皇家精神科医学院建议感到疲惫的人减少咖啡因摄入，尤其是下午三点之后，这样能让夜间睡眠质量更好。
Finally, if you do find yourself feeling overtired constantly for days or weeks, you may be suffering from fatigue or exhaustion.
最后，如果你连续数天、数周都持续感到过度疲惫，你可能正饱受疲劳或精疲力竭的困扰。
If so, it could be a good idea to visit the doctor in case it's a symptom of an underlying health issue.
如果是这样，最好去看医生，以防这是潜在健康问题的症状。
However, for most of us, the odd day of feeling overtired might be fixed with a change in lifestyle and a few good nights' sleep.
不过，对我们大多数人来说，偶尔一天的过度疲惫，通过改变生活方式和几晚优质睡眠就能得到缓解。